The highest temperature for today is 19 degrees.
今天的最高溫度是19度
So, I won't get cold with just a jacket on.
就算只穿一件夾克也不會太冷
The long winter has passed.
漫長的冬天離去
Spring is finally here.
春天終於到來了
This must be what Grandpa meant
爺爺之前說的
before this.
就是這個吧
You've just gotten your license. So, you may not know this.
因為妳才剛考到駕照 或許還不知道
But the best time to ride a motorbike is during that short period
其實最適合騎車的時期 就是季節更迭時…
when the season changes.
那些許的時間
When the season changes?
季節更迭時
Is it around April?
是四月左右嗎
That's right.
沒錯
But the time is slightly different for each region.
不過每個地區的時間還是略有不同
In this region, when it's almost April,
這一帶是快要四月的時候
you won't feel cold with just a jacket on.
大概是穿一件夾克也不會覺得冷
But it's not so hot that you'll sweat.
卻也不會熱到流汗的時期
Here, you'll sweat easily come April.
這裡一到四月就滿容易流汗的
So, it's really just a short period of time.
真的是"些許"的時間呢
Now,
現在
it's that short period of time.
就是那些許的時期
Today, I'm going to have a long-awaited solo camping.
今天要來場久違的單人露營
LAID-BACK CAMP SEASON 3
《搖曳露營△ (第三季)》
EPISODE 9: BIKE AND CHERRY BLOSSOM TOUR JUYA HOT SPRING CAMPING GROUND
(第9話 機車旅行和賞櫻巡禮) (十谷溫泉露營場)
Do I go down here to reach the camping ground?
露營場是要從這邊下去嗎
This is too steep. It's scary.
這也太陡了吧 好可怕
Do I still have to continue down?
還要繼續往下嗎
Finally, I reached the camping ground.
終於到露營場了
Although it's not big,
雖然占地不大
there are many cherry blossom trees here. It feels very relaxing.
但還種著櫻花 是個讓人很放鬆的地方呢
Although I heard that this place is quite secretive,
雖然有聽說這裡是個秘境
I didn't expect it to be empty.
但真的一個人都沒有呢
After all, the entrance is narrow and steep.
畢竟入口又窄又陡
It's not easy to come here.
想到這裡來確實不容易
But thanks to that, I have the place all to myself today.
不過也拜此所賜 今天又能包場了
This is...
真開…
Forget it.
罷了
Let me set up the tent quickly so that I can sit down and relax.
還是趕緊搭帳篷 坐下來放鬆一下吧
It's done.
完成
Is it car campers over there?
那邊的人是汽車露營客嗎
I want to try that style of camping in the future too.
將來我也想試試那種露營方式呢
It feels like it'll be easy to pack up as well.
感覺整理起來也很輕鬆
I left home in the afternoon. But it's just one o'clock right now.
明明是中午過後出門的 現在居然才一點啊
I better go and take a walk.
果然還是去散散步吧
Is she a middle-school student?
她是國中生嗎
Even a middle-school student is doing solo camping now.
居然連國中生都跑來獨自露營
This trend is really hitting us hard.
這陣風潮果真不得了呢
No. A middle-school student can't ride a motorbike, right?
不 國中生不能騎機車吧
So, is she a high-school student?
所以是高中生嗎
I don't think a high-school student will camp at this kind of place for the trend.
這陣風潮應該也沒有紅到 讓女高中生跑來這種地方露營吧
Is she a university student?
那是大學生嗎
Okay. We'll think of her as a petite university student.
好 就當作是個嬌小的大學生吧
Here. The prawn fried rice is done.
來 蝦仁炒飯好囉
Thank you.
謝啦
Bon appetit.
我要開動了
Your cooking has become so delicious because of camping.
居然能讓小谷煮的料理 變得如此美味
Camping is amazing.
露營果然很厲害呢
Well, do you want to live here temporarily?
那麼 要暫時住在這裡嗎
RYUJIN BRIDGE, RYUMON BRIDGE
(龍神橋 龍門橋)
RYUMON BRIDGE
(龍門橋)
This bridge is so unique.
這座吊橋長得真奇特
RYUJIN BRIDGE
(龍神橋)
So, I can go all the way
原來這條路
to the hot spring up there through this bridge.
會一路通到上面的溫泉嗎
But it looks tiring. So, I'll pass.
但是看起來很累人 我就不去了
This is terrible.
這也太過分了吧
They don't have a caretaker here.
這裡可沒有管理員耶
I can't believe it.
真是的
What is that girl doing?
那孩子在做什麼呀?
I don't have enough garbage bags to bag all the trash here.
我帶來的垃圾袋 根本裝不完這些垃圾啊
And I'm riding a scooter.
而且我騎的是速克達
I don't think I can take it back with me.
應該也沒辦法全部載回家
Good afternoon, what are you doing?
午安 妳在做什麼呀?
Hello.
妳好
Someone left their trash here?
竟然有人把垃圾丟在這裡啊
Miss, you came here on a scooter, right?
小姑娘 妳是騎速克達來的吧?
Let us deal with the trash.
那些就讓我們帶回去丟吧
Really?
真的可以嗎
Yes. After all, we drove here.
可以…畢竟我們是開車來的
Besides, we have some trash from our camping too.
而且我們露營時也製造了一些垃圾
There's no caretaker in this camping ground.
因為這個露營場連管理員都沒有
If there's trash here,
要是有垃圾留在這裡
this place will be closed down soon.
應該用不了多久就得關起來了
When someone is new to camping,
新手剛開始露營時
if they aren't with someone who's more experienced,
要是周遭沒有露營過的人在場
there'll be unexpectedly a lot of things that they don't know.
確實可能會出乎意料地 不懂某些事呢
For example, how to take care of the leftover coal.
例如餘炭的處理方式
But leaving trash behind is terrible.
不是 但那也太過分了
Although it sounds like we are good at this,
雖然講得好像很了不起
we've only started camping last year. So, we are quite new to it.
但我們其實也是 剛接觸露營一年的新手而已
I see.
這樣啊
But
不過
fortunately, we know a friend who loves camping.
幸好我們的熟人裡 有人很喜歡露營
So, we've learnt a lot from him.
因此從他那邊學到許多事情呢
About how to clean up after camping,
關於露營的收拾作業
he has said something remarkable.
那個人說過一句名言
When you leave, don't leave any trace behind
撤除的時候不准留下痕跡
as if you are being tracked by an assassin.
要當作自己正在被殺手追殺
An assassin...
殺手…
But it's easy to understand.
不過 總覺得很好懂
Comes to think of it,
話說回來
are you a university student who's studying nearby?
小姑娘 妳是這附近的大學生嗎
No. I'm a high school student.
不是 我是高中生
But I do live nearby.
不過確實住在這附近
So, you are a high-school student.
原來妳是高中生啊
It seems like you are very used to camping solo.
因為妳好像很習慣自己來露營
So, we thought that you were a university student just now.
我們剛才還在討論 妳是不是大學生呢
I see.
原來如此
"BLACK COFFEE" So bitter.
(黑咖啡) 好苦
I'm sorry. It must be bitter to you.
抱歉 應該很苦吧
I have sugar here.
這裡有砂糖喔
I'm sorry about that.
不…不好意思
I heard that if you like bitter things,
聽說之所以會覺得苦的東西好喝
it's because your tongue has become less sensitive as you age.
是因為上了年紀後 舌頭會變得比較不靈敏
It means that you are still young.
這代表妳還年輕呢
I thought you loved your black coffee, Ogawa.
咦 小川小姐不是黑咖啡派的嗎
Comes to think of it,
這麼說起來
when I first started camping,
我剛接觸露營時
my grandpa told me
爺爺也曾經告訴我
to bring back everything I brought to the campsite from home.
要把從家裡帶來的東西全部帶回去
It'll be nice if more and more campers think like that.
會這麼想的露營客 要是能越來越多就好了
Let's pull myself together
重振精神
and start making some camping food.
來做露營料理吧
Her lunch for today
今天的午餐是…
is spinach and tomato pasta that can be cooked with just a camping cooking pot.
用一個露營鍋具就能做出來的 菠菜配大量番茄的義大利麵
Hello.
妳好
Rin.
凜
These are our souvenirs from the Mizugaki camping trip.
這是我們去瑞牆露營的伴手禮喔
We use these tomatoes to make pizzas
我們用這個番茄做了披薩
and they were delicious.
真的超好吃的喔
Let's start cooking.
開始料理
First, fry the bacon in the pot until crispy.
首先 將培根倒入鍋具裡炒至酥脆
Then, add a spoonful of olive oil,
接著倒入一大匙橄欖油
garlic paste and sliced hawk-claw chillies and turn up the heat.
以及蒜末和切片的鷹爪椒 並開火加熱
Next, add a medium-sized tomato that's cut into four into the pot.
再將一顆中型番茄切成四塊後 放進鍋裡
Mix the ingredients until they are fully cooked.
一邊攪拌一邊燉煮
Girl.
Girl(少女)
Girls.
Girls(少女們)
Garlic.
Garlic(大蒜)
Then,
然後
when the tomato is soft and mushy,
等番茄煮到軟爛後
add spinach and 200cc of water.
加入菠菜和200cc的水
Sprinkle some seasoned salt and cook until it's boiling.
以及香草鹽 讓它煮到沸騰
Next, break 100g of pasta
接著將100克的義大利麵
into two and cook it in the pot.
折成兩半後 放進鍋裡繼續煮
No Italians are watching me, right?
應該沒有義大利人在看吧
Right before the pasta is fully cooked.
在義大利麵快煮熟前
Add two medium-sized tomatoes that are cubed.
放上兩顆切丁的中型番茄
Then cook it over high heat to evaporate some of the water.
再用大火蒸去一定程度的水分
Is adding three tomatoes too much?
一次加三顆番茄會不會太多啊
Lastly,
最後
"A ONE-POT RECIPE" add half a tablespoon of olive oil
(用一個露營鍋具就能做出來的) 再用二分之一大匙的橄欖油
"SPINACH AND TOMATO PASTA" and season with seasoned salt.
(菠菜配大量番茄的義大利麵) 和香草鹽調味
And you are done.
就大功告成了
That's great.
很好
"MY FIRST OUTDOOR MEAL" Hi.
(我的第一道野外料理) 嗨
"100 SIMPLE RECIPES" I haven't used this book in a long time.
(100種超簡單食譜) 是說 好久沒用這本食譜了
Bon appetit.
那麼 我要開動了
The pasta sauce made from the mushy tomato
完全燉成泥的番茄
and the half-cooked tomatoes
跟半熟番茄混和而成的醬汁 附著在義大利麵上
is simple but delicious.
簡單又好吃
The tomatoes taste great.
這番茄真不錯
The cherry blossom season is almost here.
差不多到賞櫻季了呢
What are you doing?
妳在幹嘛啊?
I didn't realise
我之前都沒注意到
that only the top of that mountain was covered in cherry blossom trees.
那座山好像只有山頂 種了特別多櫻花耶
You are right.
真的耶
Is there anything over there?
那裡是不是有什麼東西呢?
I think there's a temple or shrine over there.
我記得好像有寺廟或神社
I'm curious now.
總覺得好在意
Should I ride a bike there and check it out tomorrow?
明天要不要騎腳踏車過去看看呢?
Nadeshiko, are you free tomorrow?
撫子 妳明天沒事嗎
I'm not working tomorrow. So, I'm free.
剛好明天也沒有打工 很閒喔
Do you want to go on a cherry blossom drive this year?
那今年也要去賞櫻兜風嗎
Yes!
好啊…
Cherry blossom tour...
賞櫻…
I'm going on a drive today, and I'll go camping tomorrow.
今天去兜風 明天去露營
I'll be enjoying the cherry blossom view this whole week.
這禮拜都在賞櫻呢
It's packed.
已經客滿了
Delicious...
好好吃
It's time to depart.
差不多該出發囉
Delicious.
好
I want to climb the stairs, Sakura.
姊姊 我要爬樓梯上去
I've arrived!
抵達
Your stamina has improved.
妳的體力真的變好了呢
UTSUBUNA PARK, MALLET GOLF COURSE
(內船公園 木槌高爾夫球場)
All of the flowers are blossoming.
姊姊 櫻花全都開了耶
This is what we saw from our home. So, this is the cherry blossom.
原來之前從家裡看到的 就是這裡的櫻花啊
I never thought that there would be a park here.
沒想到這種地方居然有公園呢
Since it's so well hidden,
既然在如此隱密的地方
is it a secret park?
該不會是什麼秘境吧?
After all, it's not easy to drive here either.
畢竟開車來也有點辛苦
Maybe you are right.
或許真是如此呢
Very good.
很好
It's a great photo.
拍得很不錯
Let's go to the next place.
那我們去下一個地方吧
Okay.
好
By the way,
對了
Aki told us that if we wanted to view some cherry blossom,
小明之前說過 如果要在這附近賞櫻
we should go to Mt. Minobu.
去身延山準沒錯喔
I think the cherry blossom tree there is quite famous.
那邊的大枝垂櫻好像還挺有名的呢
MT. MINOBU, KUON-JI
(身延山久遠寺)
It's huge.
好大喔
FULL, ONE-WAY
(客滿 單行道)
I'm sorry.
不好意思
The parking lot ahead is full.
前方的停車場客滿
There's no way for you to stop.
已經沒地方可以停了
What should we do now, Sakura?
怎麼辦 姊姊
Okay. I'll turn right ahead there.
好的 我會在前方右轉
Aren't we here to view the hanging cherry blossom of Mt. Minobu?
我們不是來看身延山的枝垂櫻嗎
Since there's nowhere to park, we have no choice.
既然沒地方停車 那就沒轍啦
But even if we can't go up,
不過就算不上去
there are still trees planted on the roadside nearby.
這附近也有沿路種了幾顆
We can view them while we drive.
我們就邊開車邊看吧
Okay.
好
Although we can't go up, this is still a feast to our eyes.
就算不去上面 也能大飽眼福呢
I'm going on a cherry blossom drive with my sister now.
我現在要和姊姊去賞櫻兜風
A cherry blossom drive.
賞櫻…兜風
IT LOOKS BETTER FROM OVER HERE.
(這邊拍起來比較漂亮喔)
I accidentally fell asleep again.
不小心又睡著了
Let me pack up and go to the hot spring.
收拾一下去泡湯吧
After all, the hot spring is only open until two in the afternoon.
畢竟純泡湯只開放到下午2點
Okay.
好了
Those two people have left.
那兩個人已經回去了啊
I haven't had a laid-back solo camping in a long time.
感覺很久沒這樣悠哉地獨自露營了
I'll come here again for my next solo camping.
下次獨自露營時 再來這裡吧
The hill is so steep that I think my scooter can't make it.
坡…坡度太陡 感覺快騎不上去了
There are many steep slopes around here.
這附近整體上有很多陡坡耶
TOGE NO YU HOTSPRING RESORT, OPEN
(民宿峠之湯 營業中)
Finally, I've arrived.
總算抵達了
Miss.
小姑娘
Are you the one who called to make a reservation?
妳是打電話來預約純泡湯的人嗎
Yes.
是的
That'll be 700 yen.
泡湯是700圓喔
Here you go.
給您
The hot spring is over there.
浴池在對面那邊喔
Thank you.
謝謝
Enjoy your hot spring.
請慢慢享受
THE SECRET HOTSPRING AT THE TOP
(秘湯 瞭望之湯)
It really has the hot-spring-in-the-mountain vibe.
有種The山中溫泉的氛圍
This hot spring spot is amazing.
這個溫泉地點超棒的呢
If I come here in the morning or in the evening, it'll be even prettier.
早上和傍晚來泡 風景應該會更漂亮吧
Although it's fenced up,
雖然姑且有圍柵欄
if I fall from here, I'll get hurt, right?
但要是掉下去 應該會受傷吧
I'm going on a cherry blossom camping with Chiaki and the others tomorrow.
明天就要和千明她們 去賞櫻露營了啊
I think the weather will be good for a while.
短時間內 天氣看起來也沒有問題
Very good.
很好…
Comes to think of it,
說起來
I was supposed to go to that camping ground with Nadeshiko.
之前本來是要和撫子 去那個露營場的
But she couldn't make it because she was sick.
結果撫子感冒 最後沒有去成
I think after that, I went to Jinbagatayama.
後來我好像去了陣馬形山
So, that was almost four months ago.
所以是快四個月前的事了嗎
I'll invite you next time.
下次換我約妳喔
Although I've gone camping in many other places,
雖然這期間也去了許多地方露營
I haven't been able to invite her alone.
但還是沒能約撫子一起去
But it seems like she doesn't mind.
雖然她好像並不在意就是了
It's hard to invite someone to come along when you've missed the right timing.
這種事一旦錯過時機 就會變得很難開口呢
It's April now.
已經四月了啊
So, it's starting from today.
咦 那不就是從今天開始嗎
You are going to go for a cherry blossom ride later?
妳等一下要去騎車賞櫻啊
Yes. I'll ride around the basin later.
是的 我想去盆地那附近繞繞
If that's the case,
既然如此
I think it'll be good to go around the outside of the basin.
繞盆地外圍一圈的路線 應該挺不錯的喔
I took that route when I rode a road bike from Shimizu to Saitama last year.
去年我騎公路車 從清水到埼玉的時候有經過
It's a nice route.
是條很不錯的道路喔
It has many flower-viewing spots too.
而且也有許多賞櫻景點
A road bike?
公路車?
It's a road bike.
呃 就是公路自行車
Something like a sports bike.
類似運動腳踏車啦
A bike with this kind of handle.
就是裝著這種把手的
You rode a bike for such a long distance?
妳騎腳踏車到那麼遠的地方嗎
That's just normal.
這很正常啦
Although it takes more time,
雖然要花一點時間
it's faster than you expect.
但它出乎意料地能跑喔
When you get used to it, you can ride it really fast.
畢竟習慣後 就能騎得很快
So, that's what a road bike looks like.
原來公路車是這樣的嗎
Until last year, I still rode my bike on Motosu Road to go camping.
直到去年為止我連本栖公路 都是騎腳踏車上去露營的
But after experiencing the convenience of a motorbike,
不過自從體會到機車的方便之處後
I don't want to ride a bike anymore.
就不想再騎腳踏車上去了
Ride me once in a while too.
偶爾也騎騎我嘛
A road bike?
公路車啊
I think Nadeshiko can ride very fast with it.
感覺撫子會騎得很快
ENGINE MODEL: NADESHIKO KAGAMIHARA MAXIMUM HORSEPOWER: 43PS
(引擎 型號各務原撫子) (最大馬力43PS)
MAXIMUM TORQUE: 45.3N⋅M, FUEL TYPE: MINOBU BUN
(最大扭力 45.3N・m) (燃料種類 身延饅頭)
"FUEL CONSUMPTION RATE: ONE BUN PER 20M" She can go 20m with one Minobu bun.
(燃料消耗率 20m一個) 一個身延饅頭只能騎20公尺
"FUEL CONSUMPTION RATE IN RACING MODE" That's too much.
(燃料消耗率是競速模式下的數值) 太耗燃料了吧
This hot spring is really not bad.
這溫泉真不錯呢
Yes.
是啊
See you again if fate allows it.
那就有緣再見啦
See you at another camping ground next time.
下次在某個地方的露營場再見
Okay.
好的
The cherry blossom drive is going north.
賞櫻兜風 正在北上
Let me go on a cherry blossom ride too.
那我也出發去騎車賞櫻吧
NEXT EPISODE: CHIKUWA, TRAM AND CHIAKI SOLO CAMPING
(下集 竹輪和電車和千明的單人露營)
WHEN ENJOYING CAMPING, BE SURE TO FOLLOW THE RULES
(享受露營時…) (務必遵守露營場和其設施的規定
DON'T FORGET TO PUT OUT YOUR CAMPFIRE AND DISPOSE OF YOUR GARBAGE.
(別忘了滅火和帶走垃圾)
TEMPERATURES CAN CHANGE QUICKLY, SO CHECK THE WEATHER FORECAST BEFOREHAND.
(由於氣溫可能會急速變化) (記得事先確認天氣預報)
WEAR WARM CLOTHING IF NECESSARY TO PREVENT COLD.
(必要時穿著保暖衣物防寒)